once my exploit needs a victim to
navigate to my uh site and I already
have like user interaction required I've
already paid that cost I can just like
go crazy with it like click here five
times like drag this to like stand up do
a dance you know like
do open up your webcam and give me
permission yeah exactly exactly yeah I
think we call the p with the victim
exactly
record a pod with the
[Music]
victim hey guys real quick I just wanted
to tell you about our sponsor threat
Locker now wait wait before you hit this
give forward button let me just say this
most of the stuff that holds my
attention nowadays is red team stuff as
well but I sat down with the threat
Locker team this past week to do a demo
of their EDR software and it was super
technically fascinating how this thing
works so check this out you drop this
thing on a system right and for the
first week or so it's creating a policy
and a profile for that system it's
logging all the executables uh what
child processes are being spawned uh the
files and their hashes that sort of
thing and it's creating this policy okay
then after the learning mode is up we're
in secured mode and that policy gets put
into place and anything that's not on
that allow list is immediately Auto
denied that's the zero trust piece right
so in addition to that they've got a
bunch of crazy features like ring
fencing and dynamic access controls that
would stop a malicious hacker at pretty
much every step along the way actually I
I was watching this demo and I was kind
of freaked out because I have no idea
how I would cope with getting dropped
into a threat locker system as a red
teamer anyway if you want to learn more
about this head over to threat
locker.com and request a demo and when
you do ask for my boy Andrew his demo
was super to the point and he was able
to answer all my technical questions all
right cool back to the
show all righty dude we are recording
maton bear welcome to the Pod man it's
been a long time coming yeah it's great
being here I'm super excited yeah me too
man and um so man this dock is looking
super gorgeous we were just we actually
uh you know jumped into the studio here
and we started chatting about all the
stuff and then we forgot to record yeah
I couldn't help myself so we're I was
like recing it before we installed yeah
we're going to have to we're goingon to
have to go back and redo some of that
conversation um for the listeners but um
okay where to start um let's start a
little bit with the elephant in the room
here mat which is the fact that you are
16 years old yeah the baby elephant in
the room yeah ex the baby elephant in
the room yeah and um I am going to be
177 in like a few weeks so I am getting
old you okay getting up there getting up
there but you are competing at the life
hacking events you've already been to
like what three live hacking events yeah
the AWC which is like kind of a live
hacking event and then um we had Miami
and Singapore yeah and now and now this
next one all right dude that's amazing
um what a crazy career already at 16
years old that's insane um can you can
you tell us a little bit about how that
came about because to be honest most
people at your age are just starting to
you know if they're lucky they're
starting to think oh maybe I would like
hacking and then starting their Journey
whereas you're already competing at the
world stage level for this um at 16 so
how did you how did you originally get
into this stuff and what kind of path
did you take to ingest all of this so
quickly yeah so it's a great question um
I'm naturally kind of you know curious
so and I used I used to and I still do
watch like a lot of YouTube and the
algorithm knows that I'm pretty you know
nerd sniper so it kind of throws a lot
of stuff at me trying to see if I can go
down some rabbit hole and one day when I
was like I'm not sure when but like when
I was like 14 or something like that I
was um go it threw like a hacker 101
video at me or something like that and
then I tried to see like tried to
started to watch like naham SEC and live
overflow and all of that you know
classic channels and I set myself a goal
of like I want to find the bug by the
end of the summer or something
unrealistic like that and maybe it is
realistic if if you like getting into it
and you know investing a lot of time but
like for a kid it's not really realistic
and then I I like started to do some
labs and I think it was like still when
I was 14 or maybe 15 I'm not sure like I
don't really have great memory of
thetimeline is not developed yet that's
hilarious so when you say when you say
Labs were you working on like the
portswigger labs or what kind of the
port swigger Labs on the Web Academy is
still a great resource the fa thing I
recommend them and actually I I see a
lot of people like not a lot of people
but when I hear portz Wier La mentioned
it's usually um more like the xss labs
and the SQL injection Labs or whatever
but they actually have um a really good
set of Dom xss Labs which is what I
specifically recommend and I haven't
heard as much about that so maybe it's a
bit underrated I'm not sure yeah anyways
you don't you don't hear about that too
often but they are pretty developed
because they I know the team at ports
wiger put a lot of time into the Dom inv
Vader to they have like they have some
great people on their team making those
LS definitely experts in their fields
yeah so it's really worth it if you
haven't checked out the dox ls
specifically as a great like list of
things and stuff um so I was going
through those labs um the SQL injection
ones uh the more popular ones and I was
like looking at the site of ports Wier
and I tried to put like um a quote in
the search field or whatever and it
threw an error so I got excited I
thought I had like an SQL injection or
something I submitted a bug um to
actually to Port wig
and of course it was n but the person
who three it was actually albino wax
James Kettle no
way and he was like he was super nice
about it he understood that I was like a
beginner and he actually recommended
like I think you would love our xss
loves our whatever like he gave me I
don't know if it was like um something
that he pasted in there but it was super
nice like instead of getting frustrated
with it like why I'm get am I getting
spammed by like these trash reports
putting um quotes in search fields and
calling it an SQL injection but it was
actually super nice about it and that
sort of sent me down the xss path and
all of that so wow dude that's crazy it
it's it's insane to me how many origin
stories sort of start from some hacker
some some more developed hacker some
some Pro haacker just being like kind
and doing something you know out of out
of the ordinary for some random person
right I mean that's the same story with
me is is doggy G showed up to my like
college uh cyber security club and and
and then you know here we are what seven
eight years nine years later and uh it's
you know I'm just so grateful um so yeah
it's it's definitely that's something uh
something that we need to be paying
forward in the community I think is is
helping others that are earlier on it
can it can have a lot of impact on
someone definitely and a lot of impact
on a lot of programs apparently because
because here we are um no that's amazing
man um okay wow so a lot of that was was
originally those ports swigger labs and
then like was that it then you just did
the ports swigger labs and then you were
like full beast mode and then you just
roll up and phone every program
or actually I remember I had a a really
hard time like jumping from the ls that
were like you know a single page or
something and you tried to put an HTM an
HTML injection in the comments and it
works to like a a full-blown application
where nothing works basically and you
have to go through a lot of um different
payloads and stuff uh I'm not sure how I
got there eventually like a lot of
practice I guess I'm really not sure how
um how I managed to find the bug but
actually what I do remember is uh I
submitted like some very [__] bugs to
Reddit like some stuff that I would
close as na in like in the blink of an
eye but they actually they were super
nice and they accepted it and they paid
like some even as mediums and stuff wow
yeah so that really like gave me the
motivation and from there it was kind of
steadi yeah very cool man yeah I I I
think you had an interesting point um
which is there there is this sort of
Disconnect
between the labs and reality and I think
that disconnect is largely in the area
of how many times you have to fail and
how many times you have to you know how
much time you have to spend just going
from page to page and finding
functionality that is interesting and
it's yeah yeah definitely it's not just
just like how many times you have to
spam a payload for it to work it's like
you don't have the same complexity and
um you know you don't have to get
intimate with the application like you
my man listens to the podcast that's
great yeah so you don't you know I've
been listening to the podcast for a very
long time like from that same place on
the timeline basically
um yeah um but
yeah well that that that's great man and
I I I appreciate you listening and and I
I I just kind of want to say like I
think that um I think there's a a gap in
that area that that you said you know
with with regards to
having people having to search for a
vulnerability inside of a lab system so
I wonder I wonder if there would be any
ways to improve this with like hey
um you've got a here's an application
there is a bug somewhere in this
application go go find it and when you
do this is the you know sequence to
attack it like I feel like those sort of
labs would be a little bit more
impactful still it would be it would be
definitely a step in the right direction
but you can't make a la that's as
complex as like a real world Target it
would definitely be there's a hole there
in the sort of ecosystem or whatever of
um training for B Bounty that's there
definitely a need for something there
yeah yeah I agree but and I think that's
I mean we preach it all the time on the
Pod but like I think getting out there
and failing is this the the uh you know
lab that you need in a lot of ways but
man there that takes out a lot of smart
people is is getting out there and how
much how many times you have to fail
before you start once you understand
that once you understand that that isn't
really failure because you can
logically expect for like more than say
10% of
um be honest yeah 1% yeah you can't
expect like a payload that you put in to
work like yeah if you if you just put a
payload in and it works you should get
worried yeah exactly for the program
yeah I wouldn't use the up if I were you
yeah absolutely and and I think that's
an interesting statistic to throw out
there I it really is more like the 1%
number guys uh listeners out there like
like if you look at the amount of uh you
know replay tabs I have and how many
requests I've inspected and how much
code I've read you know 1% or less of of
attack vectors are actually resulting in
a bug um so one of the first things I
told to one of my the people I'm me
mentoring right now was you know go and
look at 500 HTTP requests and and try to
write down what each one is doing and
and after you get to those 500 reps
you're going to be at a much better spot
um that's a great tip yeah yeah um all
right so that's a little bit about the
history so you started doing Labs you
started getting out there you started
failing until you got a couple nice
little wins on on Reddit I will mention
that this isn't like what I would
recommend for a beginner to do now um
there are some great um resources that
you could like supplement uh
Deport wiger Labs with because there is
some stuff that's missing yeah there's
one I don't really remember what it's
called I think Beyond xss it's a series
by I think jully right
Beyond it's a great series I love that
um I love that list of write ups and I
actually I've used one of those pages in
like a few days ago on a real world
Target a hardened real world Target so
it's useful yeah absolutely we shouted
out that that um that resource a couple
weeks ago on the Pod and I that was the
first time I'd ever seen it like a
couple weeks ago and I was like this is
amazing um and and so definitely check
that out if anybody is looking for uh
additional information on xss stuff
because I think the fact that maton bear
says this is an amazing resource uh on
client side stuff should be more than
enough for you to check that out yeah
those like it's not only about xss there
of course like that's kind of the point
of the series Beyond XS there are some
yeah there are some like
um here you start to get into more like
puzzly territory because with XS is sort
of the more straightforward of the
client side bugs where you have like
JavaScript execution and then it's kind
of game over right but you start to get
into the more like gadgety stuff like I
have a cspt what can I do with it yeah
so it's a great introduction to that
aspect of client side likeing which is I
think the most fun aspect and it's the
most unique you tend to get less dupes
doing that sort of hacking yeah
absolutely so so you said you know your
your favorite is client side stuff why
do you think that is what is it about
client side stuff that draws you draws
you to I think it's just the flexibility
there the things you can do with client
side hacking are crazy like I get some
chains sometimes with like I sent you
one a few days ago because I was so
excited about it or maybe a few weeks
but um with like 13 steps of what the
attacker site does and opening the
windows and stuff and setting cookies
and clearing them and you can't do that
same you can't play the same way with
the application when you're looking at
serers side stuff it's it's way more fun
it is there's a lot more capability
and I think um because of that it's a
lot more chainable but I think also the
nature of it being you know white box
that you have the source code that you
can see everything that's going on I
think that that does a lot more more
than I realized in the beginning of my
career because um you know when you look
at some of these more complex exploits
uh I'm just thinking particularly of a
couple bugs that chubs has has shared
with me yeah yeah I was going to mention
shs yeah it's just like you know he can
do the same thing on the server side and
the he's always team in general yeah
yeah it's it's it's stunning and so I
think um in situations like that having
white box having having the code and
being able to introspect into it is is
massive as well um but man that
chainable aspect of it is just it's it's
so fun it's it's so easy to debug and
it's super interactive that's the aspect
I love it's like you have the debugger
and the UI all in the same place and you
can like in real time input a line and
see how we change the things it's good
it is it is and with that actually um
one of the top requested things for this
episode was talking about Dev tools and
general clients side hacking tips and
I'm looking right now at two sections
that I have mega highlighted for the
things that I am most excited about and
those two sections the whole section is
just highlighted um which is great so um
talk to us a little bit about about Dev
tools and what kind of stuff you you use
in there that uh you think most haers
should know about when When approaching
a client side Target yeah so Dev tools
is definitely way more robust than you
initially think it does have a few
limitations um especially if you try to
use it as an HTTP proxy I wouldn't
recommend that
um talking from experience because
sometimes I don't want to wait for burp
to
load but it does have some um some great
features that um I'd recommend checking
out so if you're not entirely familiar
with Dev tools um the first thing I'd
recommend you to do is go into the
settings there's a little gear box there
under the three dots or whatever and it
has a ton of different check boxes and
stuff and you can enable like beta
features and it's very very useful you
have like a CSP violations St a whole
bunch of stuff that you don't see like
out of the box and once you're done like
messing around with those settings and
stuff um there are some tricks like some
very quick and dirty tricks that I like
to use while um testing with Dev tools
so if I'm trying
to like modify some piece of code in
order to test something or whatever um I
usually don't want to start um setting
up a match and replace rule for it and
also don't want want to um use the
override feature because um it tends to
be a little hard and it messes up yeah
that's been my experience as
well yeah and it's like it has a few
issues because sometimes
um you know the Integrity attribute um
yeah so you can have on a script you can
have an Integrity attribute um that
checks the check sum or the hash of the
script you could also have that in like
a CSP or something and if you change it
like change the actual file with um Dev
tools override then it's going to change
the check some of it and app will
misbehave because it's not going to be
valid anymore so what I do is I set a
breakpoint and with Dev tools there
there's actually a few different types
of break points which is interesting
there's the regular like blue um
breakpoint that will just break whenever
um it gets executed but there's also um
one that's orange a conditional
breakpoint and you can put just like a
statement there or a piece of code um in
the breakpoint when you sort of edit it
and it will execute that code if that
code returns through then it's going to
break there if it returns false it's not
going to break so if I want to like
override something for like a quick
check or something I I set like a
breakpoint there and I edit it and I
just write out the code that I want to
injector and I do like a semicolon and
the right false at the end so it doesn't
use it as a break point and it's super
quick it's like wow what the heck that's
a genius technique what the heck mat why
did you tell me about this before dude
because I wanted to save your reaction
for the PO we're farming content
dude that is nuts I thought okay so I
was reading over this and I was like oh
yeah you know conditional breakpoints
that's something that people need to
know about we should definitely talk
about that of course I'm just using it
like a normal human and just setting
conditional breaks like a crazy person
and you're like actually writing scripts
inside conditional breakpoint wow that's
that's a super cool tip you never have
to leave like your environment and it's
way like it removes friction like you
talked about I think maybe less week or
something on the bo um about removing
friction when you're testing and it's
super valuable for that W trick that's
nuts that is so exciting actually
because you know what I'm often doing is
I'm um I'm using match and replace uh to
actually overwrite parts of the
JavaScript right and and so like what
I'm thinking of a Target that I that I'm
working on um right now and I I there's
a JavaScript function that says like oh
is this feature turned on and I'm like
okay well what what if you just always
return true you know like that would be
really helpful then every feature would
be turned on instead of me having to
like you know match and replace this
whole long list of feature Flags so I do
that but then you're absolutely right
you know sometimes there's Integrity
checks and that sort of
thing for that specific use case I would
still use a match and replace because um
the log points and stuff or the I'm
getting ahead of myself the conditional
breakpoints are only executed um if the
dev tools is open it's the same with um
overides and stuff so if you just want
to test the app like the features and
stuff um match and replace is the way to
go but if you're looking at uh at the
JavaScript and you want to quickly
change some something it's it's way
quicker and way easier to do it with by
misusing a conditional very cool very
cool but I I think it's also important
to shout out the the conditional
breakpoint um actual functionality ma
which is that you can do a conditional
breakpoint right you can write a
JavaScript statement which will if it
evaluates to true it will trigger and if
it doesn't then it will not trigger so
this is really help definitely what what
I sometimes do with it um when I'm
trying to look at like some message
listener um I put like a breakpoint on
the message lener and sometimes um like
usually um you would get a ton of
different uh messages from like browser
extensions or from like the regular app
and stuff so I just like um put a
conditional breako and I will do like e
or whatever the name of the event
variable is dot like ASDF or something
and then only if it has um a truthy ASDF
property it will break so and then in
all of my testing uh messages I include
like ASDF and then you don't have to
keep pressing that like little play
button play button play button over and
over again that's great man yeah that
definitely reduces friction and
increases the efficiency of your testing
which like like we said before I mean it
just has very it has cascading effects
you know it continues you think it's
just a little small thing oh I just got
to press you know play a couple times
here but it allows your brain to to not
think about that anymore and yeah and
even more importantly um you will feel
less resistance before you do the accent
so if I'm like trying to test something
and I know that I'm gonna um have to
press like fourward 10 times I'm going
to be less likely to um to actually do
it so that's a great point it's not only
in the moment it's also it also affects
like the way you think about what you
will do yeah it so that's that's a great
point because it it allows you to go
further in your testing because you're
not getting tired as quickly like oh
okay you know I've already tried three
things I'm not going to like go through
this flow 10 you know five more times uh
I'm just going to skip it versus if if
you just have lower friction you still
are able to just go go go um so that
that's that's a great we have a lot of
different points to go through here so
we do we got to keep moving I'm sorry
what's the next one so I'm going to go
through the next one very quickly um we
mentioned regular breakpoints and
conditional break points there's also
what's called log points so you put in
some code there and it passes that code
like it's um a list of arguments to
console.log so if you put like a string
and then a comma and some variable it
will log um the string and the variable
and actually using commas in uh in
console.log and stuff is very useful and
what I usually do with this sort of um
break point I have a very specific use
case for it um a lot of the time the app
um the web app is going to have some
function that's like a conditional log
of something of something so they will
have some like logging
Library um and they will check like
sometimes they do it with um local
storage or whatever they will check if
debug mode is enabled so instead of
going in and like um checking how
they're checking whether debug is
enabled and then overriding it or
something I just set a log point in the
function that logs stuff um and that log
point will just log the arguments of the
function so if they have like a a
function called debug or whatever that's
checking whether debug mode is enabled
and if it is it's gonna log something my
log point is just going to log it
anyways so then you get a bit more
visibility into what's going on dude I
did not know this
existed and let me tell you so it might
be a new feature because I didn't know
about it to until recently yeah so so I
I've like I'm looking at this and what's
odd about this so so here's how you do
this guys um in the dev tool
you know they they got the little line
line you know row or whatever on the
left hand side I think it's called The
Gutter technically but and you click
over there and itet a break point right
well don't don't left click right click
instead and you'll see add log Point
here's oh you can right click wait wait
what are you what have you been doing um
I've been clicking on it then clicking
um on the side panel edit condition and
then you can change the um oh and then
the
oh very interesting so the reason I
never knew that this existed is what I
always do is I I click to add the
breakpoint right and then I rightclick
on the breakpoint to hit edit breakpoint
and then set conditional breakpoint but
actually if you right click after
breakpoints already set it won't show
you the option for a a log Point it'll
only show you the option for breakpoint
so instead of left clicking the first
time don't you have a little drop down
there I do I do but um up at the top
yeah I do have that but I I I never saw
that before so what what I'm going to do
now though is instead of right clicking
I'm or left click I'm going to right
click and hit add log point and that
will just add the log point on there wow
I did not even yeah it's hard to teach
me stuff about Dev tools because I kind
of live there but yeah I just learned a
new trick that's that's crazy man this
is this is um this is super helpful so
we can just do and then you said these
this input here is just essentially
console.log at that specific point
yeah and it it's not just console.log
for a specific object it like passes a
list of objects so you can put like
Comas though or something a that's great
that is helpful that is super helpful H
and then then I don't have to like I
don't have to do the breakpoint and then
go to console and then type console.log
I can just log that's super helpful man
wow um very cool all right what else we
got on here yeah another one that is
like very useful um I've actually done
this pretty recently um you can um
sometimes it's very useful when um the
app opens a new window or a popup or
something to know what specifically it's
doing like what um arguments it's
passing to window. open because um there
is some stuff you actually talked about
I don't remember when but um if if the
name of the window is guessable there
are some tricks you can do there and if
you're within the same tab group as that
window you could like hijack it um I I
haven't done it but like dude I've done
it I I'll show you a report afterwards
it's it feels so good man like when you
you know the user clicks a button or
whatever and there's just no popup and
and then it's like in your other window
in the I it's just oh I love it window
hijacking is such a cool oh oh I I see
what you mean so you make it like open
because they're they're doing like
window. open and then passing like the
Target or the name the name and if
there's already such a window in like an
if frame on your page in the same tab
group it's going to open it there right
and then what you doing you control that
that if frame then right so you can
redirect the the source of it and if
it's like implicitly trusting that
relationship with a post message or if
it's like thought you were doing was
like um let letting it open it normally
and then on your um tab running window.
open with some attacker control URL and
then the name yeah that's also but I'm
going to let you finish up no no no
that's also possible but um it it's
better when they don't even see the
popup right it just goes into your ey
frame and then you can redirect it and
so um you know one of the bugs that I've
seen before is uh It'll like like the
user will click a button for off and
it'll like uh you know you can hijack
that that window and put it into your
iframe and then you can respond with
your oth in there and then maybe it'll
do some action with your oth code right
so then you can snag information that's
now attached to your account instead of
attached to the victim's account oh um
yeah that's really cool it's it's csing
them with yeah exactly that's fun um and
so that that's that's a fun one and then
also sometimes they just trust the
response and just you know embed it into
the page or whatever or like give you
access to some post message listener um
which is really it's definitely very fun
when you start to get into those areas
where the dev doesn't expect any
malicious input to be like even in the
equation yeah like they think that they
already verified it and all of that
so when you start having the and
sometimes like post message protocols
like the communication can be very
complicated like they're building a
whole um protocol on top of post
messages and when the developer doesn't
expect an attacker to be there that can
be like very fun to exploit very very
impactful indeed I wonder what you're
talking about right right now Matan I
wonder maybe you'll see a show and
maybe sounds like a very Sim similar
situation to one that I'm kind of
familiar with right now so did you find
one recently who knows who knows we
might be doing the show in together yeah
I really hope we're not going to dup
each other because I was actually I
mentioned it to nugi specifically if
someone is GNA dup me on this it's gonna
be Justin I found the open redraft so uh
you know there's oh there's some there
is some uh well we we'll save that for
the post post my like um post message
stuff is on the the Target oh is it
really oh so we're not ding each other
okay that's good that's good that's good
yeah um okay awesome so uh essentially
just to tldr this tip because we kind of
got got carried away here was yeah let's
let's move through the other ones
quickly uh was was that you're
essentially so what you've got in the
dock here is you're using saying you're
overriding window. openen with a call to
debugger right oh yeah I forgot to
actually mention what the trick was yeah
yeah I got you though I got you so and
this is actually something that I think
is really really interesting for people
to know about um is is you can trigger a
debugger um uh you can trigger a
breakpoint by using the I don't know is
it a keyword
debugger it's it's not a function call
right yeah it is yeah um so that that
will trigger a breakpoint if you just
type debugger that's it um it's very
useful because it will
trigger um if you have like a weird
context where your code is running like
maybe on the csti or something like that
yeah yeah um if you put like a if you
manage to make it run debugger then you
can like look at that and see understand
the context way better yeah very cool um
yeah I I think that debugger tip is is
really helpful um I I forgot to tell you
before this episode to get some water
too and I'm hearing you coughing so get
get some water uh while I while I'm
yapping for a second um no I I have some
yeah you have some good good good um
yeah so debugger chip super helpful I
think that one's good and we moved past
this one that I'm highlighting right now
in the dock and I want to I want to go
back to that talk to me about about uh
on before unload breakpoints so it's
very similar to um to what we just
talked about with window. open um if
you're trying to like
figure out
um some there's actually a few different
use cases for it one is like if um the
app is moving very quickly like if it's
if you're getting redirected
um a lot of times like during an
overflow or something like that and you
want to understand like what's going on
at every like stage of the way um you
can set a break point and the way it's
actually done it's a bit complicated you
go to um to the dev tools and it's like
in the sources
panel okay you have
um in the uh menu on the left you have
um right above CSP violation breakpoints
you have event listener breakpoints
right and you can go there and you can
expand the load category and you click
on you check before unload yeah okay
before unload and then once the page
redirects itself like with a setting
location or something like that before
that happens it's going to break point
it's going to like break on dev tools
and then you can see
like um how are they redirecting what's
happening like on the page and it slows
down and it's like you can actually
understand what's going on yeah that's
the one of the worst things is like when
you you try to go to this page and it's
got some weird functionality on it but
it just keeps freaking redirecting away
and you can't actually get Dev Dev tools
to like open properly and do stuff so
this will um this will be super helpful
for that and sometimes go ahead yeah
sometimes it's even more annoying it has
like a timeout of like five seconds or
something and then you try to like
really quickly go through the uh code in
like 5 seconds and save it or something
right have you um so I told a friend
about this recently and he didn't know
and he was freaking out but did you know
that you can spam Escape uh on a page
that is redirecting and it will cancel
the
redirect really oh
because it's like clicking the X on the
um on the URL bar oh I don't know I've
never clicked the X on the URL bar I
just hit Escape Escape Escape Escape
escape and while it's loading the page
you're like canceling the request all um
oh yeah yeah it is like that okay I'm
clicking it right now and it yeah huh
very interesting yeah that's nice I
haven't actually thought about using
that yeah yeah so that that helps
sometimes when you're like stuck in AIT
I it's not related at all but I just
remembered some trick that I am hit me
man that's what we're talking about here
hit no it's it's not related to Dev
tools at all I I have no idea how I just
remembered it but it was actually a
trick
was the origin story of the trick is um
I was helping someone download photos
from Google Drive to their phone and the
way I did it is like I I click on
download and then Safari on mobile has
like a little popup and it asks you
whether you want to download the file or
view it right and I've seen that popup
many times but for some reason in that
like moment I stopped and I thought
about it for a second and a a common
problem you have is if you can like
upload a file or something no way M are
you kidding me can you do this with an
it's not as crazy it's not as crazy as
you might think but if you can upload a
file
somewhere and but that file has like a
Content disposition header if you try to
make a user navigate to it to trigger
like an xss or something it will not
work it will download it right and what
I really it is like if Safari asks you
whether you want to view or download it
will it ask you if you like have an HTML
file or something so apparently what
happened
is Safari thought about that like the
developers have thought about that
scenario and for most content types it
will ask you whether you want to view it
or download it but there's a black list
of which ones um it doesn't allow you to
click on view but the is one specific um
content type that I did find I don't
remember which it is I have it don't
remember which it is I I have it I have
it on my um on my chat with I have it on
my chat with Johan I sent it to him um
with Johan I Che go get that right now
because I I need that it doesn't trigger
xss it doesn't trigger xss it will let
you inject HDML but for some reason it
doesn't run JavaScript it's super weird
oh that sounds super
that that HTML injection is
like it will be in the I think the URL
bar will show the vulnerable site so you
have impact out of a Are you seriously
dropping a safari zero day on the Pod
right now like what are you doing maybe
I don't know I mean there's plenty of
safari zero days to go around don't have
to get cheap about those oh man the the
um the so did you try the image/ SVG
Plus ml content type do that yeah yeah I
tied a few there's a there's a list of
um content types that let you um xss I
don't remember it's on some GitHub repo
it's a super useful list yeah I used it
on um on the Shopify bug on oh really oh
nice that's great man yeah I I'm very
interested to know what um the the
content type is for that uh so yeah I'm
trying to find it go go for leaving your
Hing yeah no you're good you're good if
we have to oh yeah it's so it's
interesting because I'm not sure yeah
it's text SL XSL I think XSL oh uh the
so is that the transformation language
for yeah that's XSL yeah yeah it is so
you can you can make the server respond
with that if you upload an xss file I
think right um I'm not sure because I
haven't actually tested it but I think
if you would upload
XSL file it would respond with that and
the the most weird thing about the to
functionality is if you don't specify
the content disposition header and you
put an an xss payload in there it will
trigger and it will xss but if you
specify the content disposition header
and then pick view it won't run the
JavaScript really and it won't even let
you iframe stuff or anything but it will
run some sort of sandb HTML in there
yeah it will let you like Ed images and
stuff I haven't checked I haven't
checked forums which is interesting fors
would be interesting if frames would be
interesting in like
object but it's definitely like CSS
noteworthy CSS may I don't know but like
you don't have anything to leak yeah
yeah that's interesting maybe it would
help you um fish someone though maybe if
it gets con with a doent like like maybe
you have like
a yeah maybe there's oh yeah maybe if
you have like an injection into yeah but
then you wouldn't be able to specify the
extension of that file you yeah that's
true but I wonder if um if uh password
managers would autofill it I wonder if
it's like considered same origin that
would be a
sick password manager Auto fills it and
then you it with CSS injection oh my
gosh W CSS injection yeah yeah that
would be crazy oh my gosh wow so we just
took like on live we just took a b class
that's like completely ignored nobody
talks about it oh man and yeah yeah
that's great and I mean the funny thing
is um Johan he was like he found a bug
like this and usually you like Auto
ignore it
but for some reason he asked me like do
you have any crazy trick for it and I
was like I was downloading images one
day as you do as you do as every story
starts also I I don't remember I don't
know why I didn't add that to the dock
but I'm glad I remembered it me too me
too okay dude we are only four four
bullets in we got to move okay what's
this next one how much time um I I have
a hard
in an hour an hour 30 so I think wow we
don't have any time yeah I think I think
we're good uh but yeah let's let's let's
keep moving um what is this next one
here um oh this is a good one yeah so
yeah it's just
um it's a section of the um Dev tools
side panel that you have to know I use
it all the time it's the call stock
section so if you know vs code it has
this this very useful feature where if
you like um control click on something
and you jump somewhere you can use um
alt and the arrows or um like you go
forward and backwards in history on um
on the browser you can use it to go um
back to where you jumped from but on in
the dev tools which is actually a
feature that I really miss um you can't
do that so you tend to get lost if you
like um you reading some uh part of the
code and you have a break point
somewhere and it triggers and you like
try to look for a string somewhere and
you start to jump around the code to
different sections it's very easy to get
lost so if you just expend the call
stock section and you click on the
uppermost uh on the uppermost entry it
will just jump to where your current
break point is yeah that is super
helpful I use that all the time and
actually while you were saying it I I
was thinking man I think there was a way
to jump back and forth
in Dev tools I would love to know that
yeah yeah it's I'm looking at it right
now I found it at one point I
thought where where was
it there's so much obscure functionality
in there is I'm looking I'm scrolling
through the um through the shortcuts tab
right now I I can't I can't find it
right now but I want to see that they're
actually got St yeah there is yeah so if
you go to if you go to um the settings
the little and then all the way down at
the bottom uh on the left hand side
there's like preferences workspace
experiments whatever and then shortcuts
so I think there's some stuff in there
um that allows you to navigate
through but I can't figure out which one
it is now so we'll have to we'll have to
go back to that afterwards and see if we
can oh yeah there it is right there it's
uh I think
control h that might not be it CR
control like open square bracket and
control closed square bracket but well
we we'll go back and we'll figure that
out afterwards but I'm pretty sure there
is a way to do that and if there's not
holy someone needs so it says jump to
next editing location and jump to
previous editing location what is what
is it it's alt alt minus and ALT plus
that's right alt minus alt plus I'm not
sure if plus means holding shift but
yeah yeah let's see let me see if it at
editing location though I'm not really
editing things yeah it does work wow
yeah does useful man I I hope you would
have told me that earlier yeah there
these these sort of things are super
nice and and allow you to feel a lot
more comfortable in your tools um yeah
maybe if you can rebind it you can maybe
just use the vs code reind yeah yeah
yeah I think I think that'll be really
good um while while you were talking
about all these things I wanted to shout
out one more um breakpoint that's kind
of interesting uh which is the xhr and
fetch breakpoints have you seen those
before or
no um I mean I've seen that it exists I
haven't um looked into
it when you're trying to figure out what
piece of JS code originated a request
you can set that break point um and it
essentially it's in that same panel on
the right hand side there's an easier
way to do that though the initiators is
that what you're talking about the
network tab yeah yeah I I I think that
is I think that is helpful and and it's
very nice to see the call stack when um
you have like a specific initiator uh
for a specific request or whatever I
think the breakpoint is also really
helpful because then you get to jump
back and forth between that call stack
uh like you were just mentioning and you
can go through I've definitely had times
where I like went to the initiators and
then set a break point of so this is and
easier way to do it yeah exactly just
like that um but that initiator thing is
really helpful okay I'm sorry one one
one one more thing uh before I I
bulldoze your podcast uh maton but I I
wanted to um I wanted to shout out a
technique that you actually taught me um
which was that I didn't know that you
could go to the application tab in Dev
tools and click on frames down at the
very bottom and it'll show you the
various frames that you have and on that
and the CSP on that page there's the CSP
which is super helpful and you don't
have to like synx highlighted and
everything yeah you don't have to like
copy it into CSP evaluate or anything
it's just like there highlighted broken
out nice and easy to read yeah I forgot
to mention it it's good that you
remember that yeah yeah no that's that's
that's really good um so should we move
on to this section yes let's do it okay
so Dev tools and general testing tricks
done now we've got General client side
hacking tips hit the goodness mat yeah
so these are just like some very general
tips I usually don't like um very
general tips because they can feel less
actionable but with my S style of
hacking it's very what I do is very
Target specific so kind of the only tips
I can give are pretty General um except
for like tricks and Shout out like like
we just did with um with the content
type little piece there but um some of
these tips are more applicable to
beginners and some just like General
good tips so what I would recommend is
and this is a pitfall that is for people
that are kind of newer to um to client
side hacking I think that this would be
a pretty common petful don't just like
dive into the JS you have minifi
JavaScript scpt for a big application
can be so huge super intimidating it's
so yeah it's super overwhelming and you
can't maybe some people can do it but
you can't just start reading it and
actually understand what it does you
what you can do and this is way more
productive and you it's a way to only
read the code that is
interesting what you have to do is
utilize as much Dynamic analysis as you
can so this means like whether it's
installing Dom loger which is um a way
to do um Dynamic analysis or using break
points or um like all of the I think all
of the um most of the tips we just gave
are like applicable to Dynamic analysis
like if you if there's um a window do
open and you're trying to understand
that functionality in instead of trying
to read the whole JS code like you would
with a source code or something and
trying to figure out where they're
opening that window set a break point on
window. open or something like that so
utilize as much Dynamic analysis as you
can and also
um you have to get to know the
application a lot of client side haing
is just talking what did you say Matan
did you say get get to know the get
intimate with application to it with the
application that's correct okay go ahead
sorry a lot
of yeah a lot of client side aing is
just hacking
and I I think for me it's like maybe a
lot of my time is spent looking at GS
code but a lot of it is just like spent
looking through menus trying to see
which functionality seems like um
interesting to me out of instinct or
something like that so don't just like
dive into the J and try to find like
sources and syns and all of that um just
from reading the JS so yeah try to get
to know the application and it also what
it allows you to do if you actually know
the application
well you need to have less you can have
less powerful Primitives um and keep the
same impact so what I'm trying to say is
say you have some application and you've
studied the Overflow of it very well and
you know that you can somehow get the
code to land on any page in a specific
domain right now if you find an XS an
xss in the domain that's great like you
have um at and stuff but now you can
have with a less powerful primitive like
licking the um refer or the location or
whatever you could achieve the same
impact and now by just know getting to
know the application and looking into
that flow which is there was no reading
JavaScript involved in that you just
saved yourself a lot of time and you
made your life way easier yeah and your
eyes aren't because you've been staring
at mini JavaScript for hour there is one
hacker that I know that just reads
JavaScript like a book uh and
and I just like the most insane thing
I've ever seen in my life but I really I
really like that tip I'm gonna I'm going
to wrap that up for the
listeners taking Dynamic analysis and
using that to inform your static
analysis right like to understanding
what pieces of code are running via VIA
Dynamic analysis and then going back and
looking at the surrounding code and the
call stack and and that sort of thing
can really help you understand help you
narrow down what pieces of code are
interesting and what is just the endless
flow that gets thrown into all of these
like wet packed monstrosities that we
have nowadays um that's that's I think
I'm way more um lenient towards Dynamic
analysis than you might expect like 99%
of my time reading JavaScript is just
like looking into setting break points
looking at the values of the different
um variables and all of that just like
pure Dynamic yeah um you mentioned D
logger Plus+ we just recently did a
master class on D logger Plus+ in the
critical thinking uh critical thinkers
exclusive tier on Discord um you've been
using that tool for a little recording
yeah I've watched the recording of that
master class because I couldn't make it
to the um the actual uh class but it was
great yeah it's very useful so so how
are you using that tool and what kind of
sources and syns are you are you
detecting on yeah so I'm actually I'm
not using it to the full potenti
Nei at all like yeah I'm I have been
using um I haven't known about all of
the different stuff you can do with it
with like especially events and stuff
there's some very interesting stuff you
can do there surround surrounding events
um but what I've been using it for is
just like query parameters um to for
analysis of messages and stuff I use um
post message logger
and for analysis of like which
um which URL parameters or um hash
parameters I can use um I use um Dom
logger and that kind of covers like all
of your
um like globally applicable
sources so are you hooking like that
like what are you doing for for hash
related stuff are you are you hooking
anything hash related stuff I I do the
exact same thing I do for search I just
hook um URL search parameters do
prototype doget and do has um so it
catches
like I want to say most of the cases
definitely not all which is why I want
to improve that um config with like to
catch cases where parameters are being
um passed with re exess or
splits and like and what actually want
to do is catch when there's a string
that gets split
onand dude I was literally just about to
say that that that is like I I haven't
seen anyone do that I think that should
be pretty doable right because if we can
just with dom logger we can override
that function right Dom logger Plus+ we
can override that function if it's got
the Ampersand character returns
something that we can get a little bit
more introspection into and then
essentially log all of the parameters
that are that are being parsed out of
any string that contains the
Ampersand yeah and it will be like
pretty high signal um which is like a
problem that I had with um other configs
that I've tried um is that there's a lot
of the code running on a page and it can
get very noisy if you hook too much
stuff yeah it can but I mean which
strings get split on ESS and suburb
parameters exactly it's pretty much just
that and I think there also needs to I
need to do some analysis of JS files to
understand like what the common flow is
because they might be like trying to
detect the question mark or something
like that or trying to detect the
hashtag before they do the split um so
maybe we need to hook that too to just
check and see what potential stuff there
could have
been yeah in my experience also um the
weirdest paring behaviors are those of
all older functionality MH and that's
definitely functionality that you don't
want to miss yeah so it's it's going to
be valuable to try to catch those as
best as you can and and did you see in
the master class there's a um there's a
way that he has it set up where it can
like pop up a little alert box when
something happens so what I'm thinking
about doing is I've just got a long
flight coming up here so I'm going to
try to do this on the flight is building
a Dom logger Plus plus config where it
will essentially just pop up on the
screen any any calls to uh uh URL search
programs. prototype. get. has or any of
those splits right so any page I
navigate to it just automatically says
hey these are all the possible query
parameters for this page that are being
pared by the client side wouldn't that
just like oh that would be amazing I
think alerts would be a bit too spammy I
I do it with like um a number like that
says how many it found like sort of like
with um with post message logger and
then I check the um Dev tools to see
which they found so we definitely should
get through this way faster oh my
spending a ton of time on each one dang
it we're going to have to come back and
do another I think we're going to get to
the um to the extension hacking stuff I
I don't think so either we're going to
we'll do another one maybe we can record
one live in Vegas that would be fun oh
yeah that would be very fun yeah yeah so
um let's move on uh in this section yeah
yeah let's do it
um oh this was this was a great one okay
so this is this is this is exactly what
I'm talking about when it comes to
chaining stuff right like uh trying to
weave your way into these like
situations where you have these super um
mangled payloads and you got to get it
past a w and there's a bunch of Tricks
so drop these drop these tricks on the
listeners this is great this one is very
fresh in my mind because I've exploited
it on one of the um programs which I
really like um I'd like used it in an
exploit
uh in many situations
um when you're trying to like escalate
an xss or maybe to exploit an xss um you
have to get like at the end of the day
you have to get the app to execute like
a big script all right so the way I do
it is I just on my server host like a
big script that I can write like um with
an ID or something easily and then you
have to get that up to execute that big
uh script so it's kind of a big step to
go from alert origin or something like
that to executing that huge script and
the easiest way that um works like 90%
of the time to do that is using the
import function it's not really a
function it's a keyword but you can just
treat it as a function JavaScript has
um uh function that just basically it's
just um xss as a service yeah I love
just like yeah you call import you put
in like your url or something inside of
that import statement in uh with quotes
like with a string and it just fetches
that um that file and just executes it
so you've gone from like fetch. text do
something and eving it just like a
single line I love that which is very
useful um so what I usually do in like
90% of the cases I like find an xss with
alert origin then I change it to do like
import and then the path to my file and
then I have like a nice way of editing
the JS file in an ID and having the page
executed um but there are some cases
where this won't work number one is like
when you're dealing with a wa or maybe
with an input that is limited in
characters or maybe in character set um
in those cases
um uh maybe the import won't work
because either the wa will block it or
maybe um
I want to say there's some weird context
as well where import just doesn't work
like it like so yeah what is that do you
know about you mean like with CSP no no
it's like like I've gotten a weird error
when I'm trying to execute import from
like within a script that isn't a mod
yeah like a module or something like
that and I haven't fully sused what that
means but like 95% of the time it works
for me there are two of imports one is
like an import where you just write
import and then a space and um and that
only works for modules yeah and that
import statement is very useful because
that UT statement automatically gets
hoisted to the top of the file so when
you could get your script to execute
before any other script in that file if
it's in the context of like an injection
into a script or something something
like that but the import statement that
I'm talking about is the more like
generally applicable one M um I think
it's called a dynamic import or
something like that where you just read
import as a function so you just call it
with brackets and I think that should
walk in I I've been using import with
with as a function call um you know for
couple years now and there are some
scenarios for some reason where it won't
work so maybe I'll I haven't ened it but
maybe it's just because it's nich yeah
it it could be Niche or there could be
some like
script delegation type delegations or
something like that where it doesn't
work because it is you know for the sort
of modularized environments but um yeah
I mean that
that function is like absolutely pivotal
to to getting arbitrary uh JavaScript
execution in most
scenarios so in the cases where it
doesn't work like say a CSP or um a w or
something what you have to do is you
have to think about like how you manage
to get a script to run in the first
place so for example recently I had um
such a good on some Target this is such
a I had a an xss um and they had I had
like an HTML injection and they had um a
CSP and the CSP had like um in the
script Source it's the loud data Ur eyes
so I inject my script I inject like
script Source data and then I put my
script there but then I was trying to
think and I was also if that's not
enough I was also like limited in
characters oh my gosh and which I love
those scenarios yeah you got to code
there's one yeah there's one really good
one on my blog um oh my gosh the four
character yeah
it's amazing yeah ridiculous anyways
um I was like limited in character in
both in character set and in payload
length length so um that was kind of
tricky but uh what I I sort of tried to
think like okay how can I um make
arbitrary JavaScript R there so the
first payload I was kind of thinking
about was maybe
um creating a script element so script
or maybe s equals document create
element script um then assigning a
source to it and then
um uh injecting it into the page but
that was too long and I tried to think
about it and then I eventually realized
that what my primitive was was basically
just an HTML injection right so what I
could do is just like
reintroduce that primitive or like re
exploit it somehow so what I eventually
did was just like get um Mal uh some
variable that has like malicious that
can have malicious content I'm going to
go through the list of like these
sources in a second but in this case I
used the window name which as an
attacker you can have control over so I
use the window name and then I just
passed it to document. write and then
what happens is like I reintroduce the
HTML injection and with document. write
you can put script tags it's not like in
the HTML where those don't work so I
just um write to the document and then I
basically have the exact same uh
vulnerability that I had a second ago
but now I'm not limited um in character
set on or in character length or
so when you're trying to get those
um those exploits to work it's really
important to think like how you manage
to get it in the first place so for
example
um if you maybe got it through a
JavaScript URI then you can do like open
and then put a JavaScript URI in there
like you should think on a low level
like how you manage to get xss to OCT
there M and in terms of like the sources
for where you could get malicious input
from there are a few options like I
mentioned you can use the name of the
current window and the way you set it
from an as an attacker you either um in
your malitia site you either change the
window. name and then redirect the
window and the window. name will stay
constant after the
redirect or you can um
open the vulnerable page and in the
window. open call the second argument
you can put a payload there and it will
be um its window name that's something
else I want to hook in d++ by the way is
any window. open that has a name uh
property attached to that's a great yeah
that's a great um idea for a config um
but anyways what I did there was
um in that case I couldn't
um get the window. name to be a
malicious value um I won't get into the
details but come on
details so um the chain was very
complicated I had like a self EXs right
and that self EXs was the one that I
said was limited in characters and stuff
right and that self excess I was trying
to get it to trigger on um on the
victim's account
so I have no idea how I'm going to um
put it into like a podcast for welcome
to my world dude it is so hard like you
you I'm a year and a half into this more
even in into do running this podcast and
I still have such a hard time taking
these complex convoluted chains and
exploits and like just talking through
them even though it's like what I live
and breathe every single day yeah um I'm
G to
though because it's very interesting
okay hold on let me let me let me go get
my
chair hey guys real quick I just wanted
to give a shout to the hacker content
team they have been absolutely killing
it the past couple months taking the
content from the podcast and condensing
it down into consumable social media
posts whether it be shorts or text posts
or whatever they've been rocking it so
uh I just wanted to give them a shout
out and let you know that they do all
sorts of cybercity content as well as
social media management they do
technical blogs they do uh comprehensive
social media management uh so if your
organization could benefit from any of
those types of services make sure you
head over to hacker content.com drop
them a line and mention the podcast when
you do to get your first month of cyber
security content marketing services for
free all right that's it let's get back
to the
Pod all right so all right we're back
story time with Matan here I'm I'm
excited so yeah give it a shot man it is
hard to put some of these things into
words but I'm gonna open the list of
steps I sent you okay um about that
specific
bug you know which one I'm talking about
I know the one you're talking about I
I'll mention this though here here is
what he the tip that he had in the doc
on this while you're pulling that up
monan yeah it it he's listing here A
bunch of ways to to to smuggle in your
your payloads into this into this xss
environment you got you got window. name
you've got opener. name got opener.
opener. name right there's a chain of
all these things you can do I'm actually
gonna go through them real quick so we
don't have to like come back from a
tangent yeah um so each one of those um
of those different um ways to smuggle
input has like it's pros and cons so the
classic one is like name which is a
super super short payload like for
characters yeah and um the window. name
has basically no length limit and you
can put any character in there um but it
does require you to from an attack to
have like an attacker's page the victim
has to navigate to an attacker's page
you can't like put a the URL of the um
vulnerable page directly and have the
victim navigate to that so that's um the
con that that specific way has and you
could also if you need more um inputs
you could do opener. name and opener.
opener. name which the attacker would
have control over and the other one
which I listed here there are a few um
you have you can add with a very short
payload a message listener to the page
that you have code execution in so you
can just write on message equals and
then um some uh variable name like e and
then do an arrow so like an equals
greater than and then the code that you
put there will have access to like an e
variable um that the data of which has
like malicious input there is there are
two cons to that um payload while it
doesn't have a length limit or character
uh limit a charet limit to the input you
can inject it does require you to have a
greater sign symbol and um you need to
have an attacker page to exploit it M
and the other one um which is useful um
is location so if you have control over
the location which you do in most cases
um you can just use location you don't
even have to use like location do hush
or anything just location because it
contains the HH obviously um and that
will not have a length limit because the
hash of a URL has absolutely no length
limit you can can put as much as much
stuff there as you want wow that's crazy
um but it does have a Char at limit um
if you've ever like me try to exploit um
some piece of code that does like
document. write location. HF you'll know
that the browser automatically encodes
so annoying absolutely
infuriating any like greater sign
symbols it encodes it so if you want to
use the ation as a source of malicious
input you'll have to pass it into
document into decode your component if
you want no charet um limitation or you
could use unescape which is a deprecated
function that does basically the same
thing and is way shorter yeah that's
what I ended up using on um the exploit
which we're going to talk about in a
second um and the last one which is like
lengthy
payload um I'm not sure in which cases
you'd use it though I did um in one case
talk to someone which had to use that
specific payload because all of the
other stuff um didn't work for him you
can um fetch an attacker controlled um
script or something and then um you have
to either await that fetch or do a DOT
then and then you have to get the text
from that
request and then you have to do a then
on that text call because it reads it
asynchronously and then you're going to
have malicious input I'm not sure in
which cases you have to use it but it
definitely does
exist um in cases where you have to use
that
specifically so let's get into our story
time let's let's do that I want to add
one more thing about this fetch thing
though I actually did end up using a
payload very similar to this the other
day and the situ was that the CSP had a
script Source on it um that included
unsafety Val or whatever uh so I was
able to get xss but uh it it did not
allow me to import scripts from other
domains um and but it didn't have a
default Source uh or a connect Source or
anything like that so I was able to just
like do a Fetch and then get the
response and then eval it in that case
you could have um used eval name or
something like that yeah that also would
have done would have been much
shorter yeah but sometimes you just
don't need it to be short right and
using fetch or something like that it is
well more um comfortable and easier
because you can just like edit the
script that you're hosting on your page
it it's it's easier to read too for the
devs yeah um all right dude let let's
let's do story time now uh What uh what
what bugs you got to got to share with
us yeah that that exploit was definitely
not easy to read yeah actually the the
triage team specifically mentioned that
it took them a while to figure out what
I was
doing which is super funny and also I
think that report got like nmi at least
like five times by H1 triage yeah um but
I had an self
xss um that had a charet limit though
most characters were allowed and a
length limit and what I was trying to do
was both get it to eval like a big
script like we just talk like we just
talked about and get it to trigger on a
victim's page on the victims like
session whatever
so the way I ended up doing it was very
complicated but we're going to go
through like the thought process so I
had the
HTML injection working on my
account so the first step to have the
victim see that page is to have them log
into to my account so that's like a must
have um so what I ended up using on that
specific Target they had SSO
functionality which is awesome you love
to see it you love to see it yeah it's
it's very interesting not only from like
a client side acing perspective just
generally there are a lot of different
um
attack scenarios with that and um you
can use it just like as a csrf login
csrf by Design like I've used that on a
few targets and just like using the SSO
as an open as
an login CSF and you could also use it
in some cases as an open redirect but
anyways I so the first step of the
attack was to use the SSO to log in the
victim to your account
and then you redirect them to the page
where we have xss and that the xss would
trigger um which is already great but um
we don't like have access to their
session because it Triggers on the
attacker session and usually what you
would do in this case in those sort of
situations and I think you talked about
it on your episode with um Yousef samuda
which is a great haer amazing um yeah
but what you usually do is like you open
a window to the vulnerable
site um before you log them out and then
you do the whole attack you open um you
log them out of their account into your
account then you accss it and everything
and then once you have code execution in
the vulnerable origin you take over the
page that you opened in advance and you
leak sensitive stuff from it like access
tokens
Etc that does have some limitations
though in this case what I was trying to
do the xss was in a subdomain and I
didn't have
any super sensitive data in the
subdomain it did have sensitive data but
I didn't have a way to impact Integrity
from that subdomain the only thing I had
was like it had a
a course policy that trusted that
subdomain so if the XS were to run in
the victim
session I could use it to like send
fetch requests to sensitive apis and
stuff and as the victim in their session
so I had to make it execute in the
victim session like I couldn't use any
weird trick of like on the attacker
session but you have a window and stuff
I had to have it in the victim session
which forced me to get a bit more
creative yeah and I'm actually very glad
that that happened because the trick
which I ended up using was kind of like
pretty globally applicable there was
there wasn't a ton of the like targets
tell it to me then Matan come on yeah
I'm getting that okay so what I did once
the victim is logged into the attacker's
account first thing I did was um wipe
all of the cookies using a cookie jar
overflow um which by the way I was
trying to use your um your little page
that um counts how many cookies you have
and it doesn't work on Firefox it
completely like um Loops indefinitely
are you kidding me
anyways anyways um and I was checking it
on Firefox because the triager was using
Firefox for some anyways um once I wiped
cookies the victim is now logged out of
um of all of the accounts but I still
have a JS execution because it's still
running the script that I have provided
um so
now um the situation that we have is
like we have a JavaScript execution in a
subdomain and the victim is logged out
of all of the accounts so then what I
did before all of the attack as the
attacker I would um take the note of the
session token value that I have and then
during the attack after I log the victim
out of all of the accounts I then set
the cookie and set it with like a
specific path so it takes precedence
precedent precedence I don't know um so
it takes precedence and um I provide uh
I fix it like the session to the session
that
I taken but how do you have access to
the session token is that yeah so is it
HTP it's not an HTP variable or cook no
it's like it is but I what I did is I
cleared all of the cookies right and
then I just put my own cookie that isn't
like HTTP only the server doesn't know
it's not HTP only it looks the same to
him to them right and
what I did is I I take that session the
attacker session and I put it on the
like specific part of the vulnerable
page and I fixated on the victim's
browser so now what happens is every
time the victim navigates to that
specific page the session that the Ser
that the server is actually going to pay
attention to is going to be the attacker
session so now it doesn't matter what's
actually going on in the browser
there for that specific endpoint the
victim is logged into my
account so now the next step was to make
sure that the victim was logged into
their account for every other endpoint
and this is where it gets actually
pretty crazy um I made sure that the
exploit can work only with like
um uh with uh a malicious like theay
payload in the location so I didn't have
to make them navigate to an attackers
page or anything just in the location
which is why I had to investigate like
all of the different ways to get
malicious um input right and then once I
got it to work only with location uh
information what I did once the session
was fixated on everything I found the
session I found a cookie on the
application that once every time the
victim logs in to the
account um the server checks that cookie
and uses it to figure out where the
victim should be
redirected oh it was actually happening
on the client but anyways that was like
the idea this is
insane the the functionality the
functionality there was like if you try
to navigate to some page but you're
unauthenticated so it redirects you
saves it in the cookie and then once you
log in it redirects you
back so what I how I abuse this cookie
um it didn't allow any origin but it
allowed like origins of the um it
allowed like redirection to um to pages
of the application didn't allow me to
redirect to an attacker page but what I
did that I fixated in the victim's
browser also with a specific part so it
gets precedence I fixated the cookie
that makes the server redirect them the
next time they log in it makes them the
server redirect them to the vulnerable
page and it also puts the a payload in
the hash of the page so
now the whole attack flow I'm gonna go
through it from the beginning because
it's hard to keep it um all in your all
in mind the victim is in their um is
peacefully using the application with
their um with their uh account now they
navigate to the malicious um page the
malicious page actually in an if frame I
didn't even have to do a window. open or
anything logs them into the attacker's
account now it redirects them to the
vulnerable page where I where they get
XS that vulnerable page logs them out of
the attacker's account by clearing all
of the cookies with a cookie jar
overflow and then it fixates the
attacker session for this specific
vulnerable page and it also fixates the
redirect cookie and then the pay just
redirects the victim to example.com or
anything now the victim forgets that the
attack even happened after like a few
days or something I made sure that the
cookies would last up to like five years
or
something um in case the victim wants to
like go on vacation in the meantime or
something um I the next time the victim
tries to use the application they don't
have any session cookies and this is
actually the reason why I made sure to
clear all the cookies so they won't like
be logged into an attacker's account all
of all of a sudden right right so now
they get redirected to the login page
and then they log into their account but
now instead of getting redirected back
to where they came from the cookie that
we have set takes precedence and the
server actually tells them um that they
should now be redirected after logging
in to the vulnerable page with a
um a payload in the URL so now they get
redirected back to the vulnerable page
and that page specifically in that page
they are logged in as the attacker
because in that page we have fixated the
cookie so for that specific page and
that specific page only the cookie that
will take precedence is the attackers
session cookie so now the situation that
we have we have a little bubble the
vulnerable page where the victim is
logged into the attacker's account and
can see the self excess and everything
and in every other page they're logged
into their account and now I can fully
exploit the co
misconfiguration and um interact with
the apis as the victim that's it Matan
that is disgusting that is an amazing
vulnerability dude crap that's a that's
a that's like a brand new way so okay
hold hold up for a second they me like a
4K bonus which was really great I I
imagine they would um so that's like a
whole new way to exploit I found that
all J in like a few days oh my gosh or
self excess okay so so the con you need
a couple gadgets you need the ability to
redirect somebody after they log in with
the cookies yeah and then that's
it yeah and and a way to L in csrf a way
to log in csrf
you already have to exploit the selfs
wow dude that's
that's let me let me just repeat it back
to you one more time so I can make sure
I got it yeah okay so you got you got
the um the login curf to self xss you
use the self xss to clear all the
cookies and set a uh a redirect cookie
right that has the payload in it the you
the user then goes to login with their
browser primed for this whole thing it
automatically redirects them oh no no
you fixate the attacker session also
with the path with the path variable
that takes precedent and then when they
go to log in they get redirected to that
page because of the redirect cookie on
that page they are only that page they
are logged in as the attacker because of
the path limitation now you have just
regular xss and now you just have
regular
xss holy crap dude that's amazing yeah
and I mean that Gadget is super common
like you see it all the time like
putting a path or even like some session
code or something in the redirect cookie
so the server knows where to redirect
you or even like a local storage um
variable often times is local storage is
also something that you as the attacker
but only if it's like same origin but
anyways as the attacker you could like
set like set and forget basically yeah
or if you can find a gadget to inject it
into um the local storage situation that
would be really cool too wow dude that's
a that's an amazing technique I'm really
glad you shared that that is a very high
value share
um that
man path I'm not sure I'm glad I shared
that path the path attribute man on
cookies is so powerful yeah that that is
clutch and also the domain the fact that
you could set like cookies for domains
that you shouldn't have access to like
yeah super super powerful um wow dude
yeah you're you're absolutely right we
are not going to get through anything in
the stock today um okay so we're going
to we're going to move move all of the
um we're going to move all of the
browser extension hacking stuff to a
different day I think and we're just
going to focus on for this episode we're
going to focus on um the rest of your
reports that you've got here and then
maybe we'll do some brainstorming about
yeah there some very interesting stuff
though yeah okay so that was sick uh
what what other ones you got man like
keep on give me give me another one do
it again yeah so
I'm already running out of breath but
yeah um do you want to do this one or
maybe another one one that one's great
um yeah it's not simple but we can do it
yeah
um all right
so what I had there um this is a bug
that sort of combines um ol with um cach
deception which is something that you
don't really see together very
often this was actually in a live
hacking event so it was very fun to find
and I didn't actually get a show and
tell for that one I got a show and tell
for a more boring bug but
um what happened there there was a a no
flow that let you
um in the redirect URI you could put it
checked whether the redirect U had a
certain prefix but um which is like the
domain that they um trust and then a
specific path where they expect the call
back to happen but it only checks if
it's starts with that prefix and you
could put like um past
traversal payloads in the rest of the
redirect
URI so then what I had is like the
ability to um in the domain where the
um callback URL should be like make the
code land in every page on that domain
whatever path I wanted and then I
noticed that domain if you hit the root
like um URL like just slash it would
redirect you to some um legitimate
domain like to some domain that had some
UI and stuff this domain was like more
of an internal
API um so it would redirect you to that
um to the main page and it would it had
some cash in front of it and I noticed
that if I kept hitting that um URL I
would get cash hits so if I went to like
slash and I sent a request the first
request would be like a miss and then if
I kept sending them I would get hits and
then I tried like going to SL a equals B
and I send it and I keep getting hits
after I send it and then what I realized
that was actually very interesting is
that the cash in the cash key
the um URL parameters weren't actually
included so what happened is if I like
went to SL a equals B and then I hit it
once and then I change it to like a
equals c or even just remove the
parameters completely I would get the
same response and that response was a
redirect to https legitimate domain.com
a equals B oh my gosh now what I could
do and what I actually did um I I just
made the victim navigate to the um to
the Overflow URL with the redirect URI
of um leg demate path SL callback and
then uh a lot of like path traversal
sequences and then what happened is the
victim navigated to that URL got
redirected to um internal API domain SL
and then all of the parameters and then
if right after he got the redirect
response I would from the same like
region or whatever I would send a a
request to just internal API path slash
I would get the cach response that
included the redirect and included the
actual URL parameters now I could just
lick the code and the ATO them dude that
is such an uncommon situation I never
seen a scenario where the cach key
doesn't include the query parameter but
the response contains the query
parameter that you put in the like what
that's so weird I mean the cas should
always include the uh search if you were
to put like a cach buster on some
specific um endpoint you would put it in
like the location search like the search
parameters I have no idea why the cash
didn't include that but I mean so what
you would do is you'd craft a scenario
where it would launch an oath flow hit
the path traversal hit this internal or
this like you know API domain where it
as the weird caching and then um maybe
hit a path that's like a unique ID or
something like that and then um and then
have the users's authorization code or
whatever attached to that and then you
as the attacker would uh hit that
endpoint afterwards and grab the code
and log
in oh my gosh yeah I mean
the bulas is called cach deception but I
didn't have to do any deception in this
case you just cached it for me hey man
which M caching this it don't don't
include the query parameters it's fine
just just how it
is that's great man that's so funny wow
dude um I think this is a really good
example of how you use chains really
effectively right is because you you're
you're noticing all of these little
niche um caveats in these various
Primitives that you have across the
scope and then you say okay you know
this primitive allows me to leak quer
query parameters and then you find a way
to to um you know land those query
parameters on that actually so let me
ask you this did which one of those did
you find first did you find the PATH
traversal or the quer Pam caching I
found the um the path traversal first
and then I tried to look for um ways to
lick it from the that domain okay and in
that domain it didn't have any
functionality like except or barely any
functionality except that call back URL
but I mean sometimes they functionality
that you forget even exist like a cash
and the redirect yeah any any
functionality except for this overeager
cash like I can cash that I to cash that
for you that that's that's
hilarious um wow dude okay very cool and
and I'm wondering I'm wondering did you
did you find this path traversal and
then up on this domain and then did you
search search search until you found
this primitive to to allow you to leak
the the queer parameters or did you like
move on to other things that sort of
thing I kind of just stumbled upon it
pretty quickly which is was was like
pretty lucky and I I never like run
um I didn't run like any cash deception
tools or I don't even know if those
tools exist but like M I didn't run any
tools on it I was just trying to check
if there was any weird Behavior there
and I stumbled upon it pretty quickly
because it was like other than the um
callback URL it was the only other um
URL I found that actually did
something wow dude that's that's nuts
what a what a crazy one um let's let's
move from there let's go to this um
673 uh one then we can talk a little
yeah I'm glad you skipped the I'm glad
you skipped the other one because that
one is complicated yeah well we I'll
mark that one for next time I'm not
going to let you get off the H without
that yeah it is um it was just disclosed
it's a bug on gitlab that has to do with
um vs
code I'm gonna try to make it sound as
boring as possible so you don't um so
you don't uh get sorry that we missed it
but um it has been disclosed on um
gitlab now so if you have to check it
out as soon as possible you can do that
okay and which uh issue track there's
two report numbers which what other
which report number is
it um the one that got disclosed is the
one that I wrote the cve for okay gotcha
and but the report isn't actually
disclosed on AK one I asked them to
disclose it but they didn't do it yet
okay um but you can just um the web vs
code xss is a link I linked it to the uh
okay gab isue so you can put it in the
put in not the one that the bug
explanation that we're skipping so that
um so that you can go and read that all
right tell me about this uh this so this
is exactly what we were talking about
earlier actually with dom logger Plus+
hooking the URL search prams prototype.
getet right
yeah so it was an issue in like a big
company which shows you like the the
mistakes that some companies can make um
it was and I'm actually surprised that
nobody else found it but I was just
looking through some and it wasn't even
a very weird
um endpoint it was like an endpoint that
gets visited all the time like one of
the main endpoints of the main app and I
just looked through the Dom logger um
logs and I hooked like the exact same
thing we talked about like the URL
search PRS prototype get and has um just
to see which parameters they're trying
to see and there was just a parameter
named Dev so of course I tried to look
into that very interesting what yeah and
what that parameter was doing it
accepted a
URL to some Json config
file that config file had your heart is
beating fast at this point when you see
it like loads a Json config file you're
like yes yes yes yeah and that config
file had a property of a JS file and
that JS file was loaded not in the same
origin in like some sandbox origin in
but in a worker and then they
communicated with that worker and stuff
and I managed to get some Target
specific impact out of that
communication very cool so but yeah that
was interesting and it was like a free
bug yeah dude I I can't believe I I can
see here where you found that in the
dock um we won't disclose it but that's
that's crazy because that's got to be
one of the most assessed pieces of of
code like out there um so wow that that
that really just speaks to the power as
well of Dom logger Plus+ and how little
introspection um the majority of of
hackers have into what's happening in
their browser and I think that's one of
the things that I I really want to work
with the community to change d Kevin is
is carrying us all on this on this
front yeah and because just so much
stuff happens like so much stuff and you
couldn't go through all of that manually
if you wanted to right and like it
changes all the time and stuff you
couldn't go through that manually yeah
so it's so important then to have a a
built I mean this is literally an
essential tool I think and the master
class that we did at at in the Pod in
the critical thinkers Channel it totally
changed my perspective on how to use Dum
lugger Plus+ and I I went that same day
even though I was in the middle of a
live hacking event and I burn some
config files for it because it's it's
that impactful and what I'd really like
to see happen in the long term in this
sort of um client side arena is to have
a tool that's similar to like kaido or
burp right something a proxy of sorts
that allows us to see what's happening
at essential areas of our browser for as
far as security assessment goes yeah and
I think that would require like at a
certain point you start to run into
limitations of the browser yeah Kevin
already managed to do that um with his
extension um I think that would require
like a fork of chromium or whatever
which is can be hard to maintain yeah
super hard it might be it might be an
Enterprise grade product to be perfectly
honest and I would pay for it gladly you
know um and so I I think that there's
definitely some some and you know uh Dom
Invader does does this to some degree um
but I think I think there's I'd much
rather have something that just lets me
know what's going on rather than and
alerts on things and it's like more
independent like I don't like it when
tools are
too like monolithic like yeah locked
into their environment so having yeah
having to open up BP to open the browser
to do client side testing and you can
like you can't turn on and off the proxy
for that browser and the B browser that
has the um what's it called the Dom
Invader yeah built into it extension
yeah yeah I I agree so I think we need
an outside product and I it would it
would be really cool if Google would
just give us like a uh you know a
setting or something like that a flag
yeah where we could go in and just
because we we were discussing with Kevin
in the master class like um you know
there's not really a way for us to
overwrite document location.href and and
and in you know prox
like that yeah yeah um so I think a
feature flag for that would be really
really helpful and and allow um you know
extensions or whatever to to hook into
that and and gain introspection there um
so what I wanted to do with this last
little segment that we'll do here is
just kind of discuss what kind of things
we would want to see in that that client
side heads up display I'm I'm sort of
imption imption I'm kind of envisioning
a uh that's not a word
uh uh envisioning a you know a separate
application that's linked into the
browser via an extension right and
that's giving us introspection into
everything that's going on in the page
and you can sort of do this with Dev
tools already but I think it'd be
helpful to have it be an external Dev
tools is limited like I think Dev tools
needs also needs a chromium Fork
seriously sometimes yeah sometimes like
especially like I mentioned earlier in
the network tub it has like requests
that you just tells you like I can't
find that like when you try to look at
the response it tells like it says it
says like I can't find the response to
that request like why like I I see it
here like what where did it go did you
lose it like um yeah so it's that's
definitely a tricky part there um so
here's here yeah and I actually I really
liked that section I think it's like
very creative yeah so and it's actually
it would be very useful to see let's
let's let's kind of talk about what we'd
like to see there a couple things that
came to mind of course is going to be
changes in registered hand uh handlers
so like example if if a you'll often run
into a scenario and this is actually um
the sort of scenarios where I'm finding
a lot of post message vulnerabilities
nowadays as it's becoming a little bit
more mainstream well it's like temporary
it it's it's dynamically generated uh
you know and you've got a either a user
clicks on something and then it opens up
a post message listener or it's a
temporal post message listener that just
gets registered for a short period of
time and then gets closed um yeah and
there are there are some weird
conditions sometimes like um only if I'm
if the window has a parent or only if
yeah yeah exactly and so those sort of
thing you know any registration of post
message listeners or new hash event uh
hash change events is also really
interesting um because those are ways
that you can kind of get weasle your way
in there um what other handling
do we have that that kind of ties into
um what I call like Universal sources
which is something you have like in
client side acing it's like sources of
input that exist at like the browser
level and exist for every um Target
almost every Target unless they're using
cross origin opener policy unfortunately
yeah but anyways yeah so all of those
are like essential to see
um in any type of client side heads up
displays heads up display yeah so like a
hash change event or a post message
event or even and this sort of
references um some research done by um
space raccoon and a paste event um that
might require some more exotic user
interaction um but you could make a user
like paste attacker controlled input
somewhere or maybe and I didn't write in
the doc but it's also applicable um a
drop event like for drag drop event yeah
you could like um make user drag
something and then open up a new window
and make them drop it there yeah I think
that's really easy to actually have
happen to be perfectly honest you know
and maybe there's a specific set of
people that you couldn't Target you know
but like there are so many browser games
where it's like you know drag this thing
or like do you know and and I think it's
really I think it's likely that you
could get someone to do that yeah it's
all about like the way you present it
um there are like a lot of cases like
maybe upload a file or I don't know I'm
sure you could somehow convince me to
drag and drop something yeah yeah it
should be pretty simple um that it
wonder it does make me wonder then like
when does it cross the line of like if
you have a compliant user then you can
just sort of make them enter their creds
you know into your site right that's
what I don't like about um CVSs one of
the things I don't like there are many
but like um the fact that user
interaction is binary like for me as a
hacker once I get like um once I my
exploit needs a victim to navigate to my
uh site and I already have like
user interaction required I've already
paid that cost yeah I can just like go
crazy with it like click here five times
like this and drop it here like stand up
do a dance you know like do
the open up your webcam and permission
yeah exactly exactly yeah I think record
a pod with the victim exact record a pod
with the
victim that's hilarious like that dude
if uh if Riverside had a program that
would definitely be like a good one it's
like you have to get the victim on your
podcast and then oh so that's the reason
I'm here yeah oh man just just a couple
more minutes my my exploit takes two
hours to work so we're going to have to
exploit was leaking
um excess leaks all the time leaking all
your sensitive techniques character by
character um no that's good I'm already
leaking it um in my Discord chat with
you exactly um all right so yeah the
other thing obviously is like post
message conversations that one's that
one's pretty great we have that with um
yeah that's one's essential yeah yeah
absolutely you need to have that and I
think that would be it would be cool to
have a nice user interface for that too
to be honest I would totally pay for
this product like if this was you know I
would pay $50 100 I mean I don't pay for
much but I would pay $50 a month for a
product that really nailed this yeah um
definitely and and you know something
that makes post message conversations
really easy to follow and easy to track
um uh new frames that are being are
popping up on the page right that one I
actually really liked because I
personally I personally have found
myself like catched myself missing that
a lot of the time um the way I like
check which frames are available it's
just like after the page is finished
loading I just go through the elements
and see which ey frames there are but in
many cases an if frame just like pops up
and um gets removed and that sort of
stuff and then I just notice like in the
post message tracker which sort of like
logs um post message listeners and keeps
them logged after you like close them or
remove them I noticed like some frames
that I didn't even see in the page yeah
and that is something that personally
I'm currently missing all the time on sh
so yeah I'm sure there's AAL bugs like
that especially in reauthorization flows
when you get to a page you know it's
very common for them to like let me just
pop up in this if frame and do some like
ooth magic in here to like get my my
session token back out and then delete
the if
frame so I think that that could be
pretty common and I think also a great
way to see the frames is just sources
and then on the left hand side you know
where in the page tab um you know you
have like all the logs also the frames
that are removed it it doesn't log the
ones that are removed but it does allow
you to show the ones so if you have that
open when you navigate to the page
you'll see it like we just said open in
the application tab yeah oh in the
applic will it will it do it in the
application tab too oh yeah it will but
it that doesn't that doesn't include
ones that were
ephemerally I'm talking about in the
sources tab D so click click Dev tools
go to sources and then you see on the
left hand side where it says
top yeah so it will show the other
frames over there as well if you have an
i and even even ones that were like
popped up and removed no not that yeah
so just just just normal ones uh just
ones that are currently in the page yeah
so if you click this so I just like
control F for if frame yeah yeah yeah
that'll do it too so new frames um what
do you think about local storage SL
session storage read and wres I feel
like that's a little bit
yeah it's more Niche it's pretty rare to
have um gadgets that let you control it
a bit less rare to have gadgets that let
you control some part of it um I
actually have one I can show it to you
in in the um uh back Bound in the LH
scope yeah um a certain like um local
storage um
pollution uh yeah like a specific um
setting a specific key that holds like a
Json object with some settings um
there's a listener that lets you set it
um but I have been actually it's pretty
tough to see like where they're using it
so maybe this could also be implemented
with uh maybe a d logger config but it
would be very noisy like logging um
which is also might be a problem with
like a heads up display like that
that local storage gets used gets used
all the time with all sorts of different
keys and it's G to be um pretty noisy
but if you grip for like a certain key
it will be fine yeah and I I think also
cspt like tracker the the the tool that
we have in the critical thinkers Discord
um you know what that does is it looks
at the you know the the path the queer
parameters the hash or whatever and then
it traces those values into fetch
requests or exit HR requests or you know
frames that are happening as sub
resources and I think something similar
could be implemented here um
unfortunately there are some some
Frameworks that just literally put the
current page in a local storage you know
uh cell or whatever so that would be
super noisy but like being able to trace
values from like okay you know this was
in the hash and now it's in the that
should be pretty high sign right from
the hash from
yeah I think actually the cspt
extension um is maybe
like one one specific use case of that
you know technique and once you have it
built out like you have it in your um
cspt extension I think it's going to be
very valuable to like generalize it a
bit add like um iframe Source Setters or
like location things like all the
basically the universal s because
browsers sort of they have like the
universal sources which is what we
talked about like location search and
location in general and post messages
and all of that good stuff that we want
to have visibility into but they also
have like
um um Global syncs so if you already
have the ability to trace some of these
sources maybe not all of them um because
something like post messages would be
will be very hard to trace but if you
have it built out like you have it with
the extension I think it's going to be
very interesting to start adding some
other it gets a little bit less High
signal though when we do that that's
that's the really tricky part for this
heads up display if someone were to take
on this project it's a balance the
biggest challenge would be figuring out
what is high signal and then also making
sure that your users can customize the
extension uh in the app thoroughly so
doesn't end up like belp issues
basically exactly exactly I didn't you
said it not me you know like like
exactly um yeah but yeah this page
doesn't have a sec whatever but you know
it's interesting though because um James
had a point James Kettle had a point
when when we were discussing something
recently about the new uh character um
character set charet yeah the Char Set
uh uh thing research that came out did
see that logged in the um in the Bel
issues yeah was soar sonar research came
out with that that um that research on
essentially being able to dynamically
change the the character set and convert
backslashes into Yen symbols um amazing
but not as common as you would think it
would is because almost all pages are
actually specifying the uh character set
that's being used um but James when we
were discussing it James kind of popped
in and said hey um you know burp has
been alerting on on the fact that there
is not a specified character set uh by
default for like 10 years and I was like
okay well that's really interesting and
that is a cool but it got Lo it got lost
in all of the other um yeah loged issues
but it makes you wonder you know how
many of these little issues like can be
chained together and can be furthered a
little bit more and aart yeah I mean I'm
sure I'm sure it's not as easy as I
managing it and I'm sure if I was a
developer of burp I would have done a
worse job and because it's a it's a very
hard like issue and I mean um I don't
judge them for like it being a bit noisy
and I mean for what it's worth they did
they do have some feature that let you
like sort by they have um severity yeah
for every issue and they also have
confidence which I really like I think
it's good design so yeah so it you might
have like um I don't know the scanner
thinks that there's an sqli in in there
which you would like be very interested
in that in that but um it has different
levels of like how confident it is so if
it only saw like an error message that
looks similar or I don't know how it
does it but like um then you might have
it be like a critical issue but um have
it uh be like low confidence which is
good design yeah I I totally agree I
really I really like that design um from
burp all right so yeah and I I think
just going back to the conversation of
like this kind of needs its own chrome
fork um I really do think that if if
someone was to build this it would be
there needs to be some way to grab
introspection into uh you know window
location. H or whatever um because I I
think that would be extremely valuable
and would further further the product um
and sort of the reason for that is
really just want to know what inputs we
have to a specific client side path
right and you know hooking URL search
programs is great but URL search
programs hasn't been around for forever
um so we really need a you know access
to window location. HF custom parsing um
which should be able to be done uh if we
can override if you can apply you know
the proxy to that actual attribute um
which you can't by default in chromium
so I don't know maybe we need to hit up
the guys at Google and be like hey look
can you just make this happen please
like this would be huge
so I'm currently um you sort of reminded
me of this with the um encoding
differentials research from son and I
saw there was one Wikipedia article
which I'm currently trying to find we're
going to add it to the description later
but um that has sort of a list I don't
think it's a comprehensive list there
weren a lot of um different Char sets in
there but it's just a list of a few
different Char sets and the Escape um
sequence that you can use to um change
into those CH sets and from my testing
um all of the ones that I've tested from
the article have worked so it's
definitely because the um the article
only lists a few and like maybe two but
um the research can be generalized to a
few more Chets if you need them for some
reason wow dude that's pretty sick like
if if the certain application supports
it or something like that that's pretty
rad um all right dude I just realized
that I miscalculated uh the time that I
needed to end this podcast at and I am
late to the airport so I've got to go um
yeah yeah I think we we will come back
to all of this uh I think we'll come
back to this one next time too so I'm
going to I'm going to highlight this one
for next time um and Richard if you can
move this to a doc that would be great
I'm just I love I love critical thinking
podcast man I'm just like talking to my
uh to my editor like right on the POD
live minions all right well maton dude
thanks so much for coming on man it's
been a blast I can talk to you for
hours yeah definitely all right man um I
will see you in Vegas in a couple weeks
right yeah thanks so much for inviting
me on the Pod it's been really fun of
course man it's always a blast all right
talk to you soon peace brother see you
and that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there